<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://filbot3.github.io/xml/base.min.xml" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on Phils Blog</title>
    <link>https://filbot3.github.io/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on Phils Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://filbot3.github.io/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Mythic Bastionland With Dungeon World</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 04:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea came to me after reading Mythic Bastionland and trying to parse Dungeon World Fronts so I could build fun wilderness exploration adventures. One of my players said they did not like random encounters and wanted to focus on &amp;ldquo;the story&amp;rdquo; while traveling. Thinking about how I&amp;rsquo;ve ran wilderness travel and random encounters for other groups, I revisited Mythic Bastionland and Dungeon World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Mythic Bastionland the game&amp;rsquo;s focus is resolving Myths by encountering Omens when rolled on an encounter table. A little bit of mystery and a bit of exploration is fun for me. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be tied to Arthurian knights, so I thought a bit. Please checkout &lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/mbplaytest&#34;&gt;Mythic Bastionland Playtest&lt;/a&gt;. The full game should be out soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, I was investigating some ways to make Sandbox situations but dress them as fully realized adventures. I reopened Dungeon World and started reading about Fronts. Thinking about their structure and how Mythic Bastionland works, I determined that Myths with Omens are very similar to Fronts and Dangers and their Grim Portents. While a Myth has six Omens, a Front has 1-3 Dangers and each Danger has 3-6 Grim Portents. You can read more about Fronts in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dungeon-world.com/&#34;&gt;Dungeon World book&lt;/a&gt; or on their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dungeonworldsrd.com/gamemastering/fronts/&#34;&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt;. I think combining these two ideas will be fun and hopefully show you how I&amp;rsquo;ve used this for a few exploration adventures that focused on a higher goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WARNING&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: I write this under the assumption you&amp;rsquo;ve read the links or books for Mythic Bastionland and Dungeon World. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WARNING&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mythic-bastionland-wilderness-rolls&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#mythic-bastionland-wilderness-rolls&#34;&gt;Mythic Bastionland Wilderness Rolls&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the easiest portion to cover so we&amp;rsquo;ll say it first. Page 18 of Mythic Bastionland covers time, however what we&amp;rsquo;re interested in is the &amp;lsquo;Wilderness Roll&amp;rsquo; table. I&amp;rsquo;m going to share the modified version for this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1d6&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Wilderness Roll&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Encounter the next Grim Portent from a random Danger in this Region.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;2-3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Encounter the next Grim Portent from the nearest Danger in this Region.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;4-6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Encounter the Hex&amp;rsquo;s Landmark. Otherwise all clear.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just hang with me, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how or why we got to these wordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the explanation process is, as you enter a hex, regardless of if you&amp;rsquo;re doing one hex a day or three, roll on the table to see what happens. Player&amp;rsquo;s choose to engage, but that Grim Portent is now there and causing issues. The GM should make liberal use of their imagination and interpretation skills to figure out how or why that Grim Portent is there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fronts-as-myths&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#fronts-as-myths&#34;&gt;Fronts as Myths?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mythic Bastionland uses Myths and Omens. Dungeon World uses Fronts, Dangers, and Grim Portents. You might see that there is a difference in the levels here. You can choose to have two or three Fronts with 2 or 3 Dangers each totaling six Dangers similar to Mythic Bastionland&amp;rsquo;s 6 Myths for a given Region (Realm). This can introduce many interweaving threads and plot lines to discover and factions to interact with as part of the lonely fun, or if your table enjoys it, collaboratively. However, we&amp;rsquo;re going to Focus on a single Front with three Dangers and six Grim Portents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Front in this case can be thought of equivalent to an &amp;ldquo;overarching adventure&amp;rdquo; or thing happening in the region, the big picture. Regardless this works the same. We define our Front as per the Dungeon World book, or if you&amp;rsquo;re inspired, use random prompts and season to given context or desired style of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dangers&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#dangers&#34;&gt;Dangers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I read DW p.185, is to design your Dangers first, then based upon the Dangers and Grim Portents is what we title the Front as. Let&amp;rsquo;s make a Danger using Dungeon World &amp;ldquo;tables&amp;rdquo; starting on DW p.187.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Danger Type&lt;/em&gt;: Planar Forces (1d5 roll).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Danger Actor&lt;/em&gt;: Demon Prince (1d6 roll).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Impulse&lt;/em&gt;: Open gates of Hell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Impending DOOM&lt;/em&gt;: Usurpation (1d6 roll).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have our Who (kind of), What, Why. Now we have some more questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is the Demon Prince?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is helping the Demon Prince?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the helpers standing to gain from helping?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who will suffer the most from these actions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answering these questions should help us figure out the Description, The Cast and setup our Stakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description&lt;/em&gt;: The Demon Prince Barlon is wanting to open the gates of Hell by using followers of the the Red Star Cult to find keys and locks scattered through the realm. The Red Star Cult believes these will open a gateway to other realms to escape to. If the locks are opened, psychically attuned people will be gateways to allow demons through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cast&lt;/em&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demon Prince Barlon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Star Cult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citizens of the Region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stakes&lt;/em&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to the citizenry of the Region when demons flood the area?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the psychic people feel this presence or activity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the corruption look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the Grim Portents, the steps being taken to achieve the goal of each Danger feeding the overarching Front big picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;grim-portents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#grim-portents&#34;&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think of some steps for how our Red Star Cult will unwittingly achieve their goal and be deceived in the end. We usually want six Grim Portents or steps to achieve the Danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSC raids local library and arcane college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychics begin turning ill and hospitals are flooded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creatures from long forgotten times terrorize country side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settlements are being uprooted and migrating to safe havens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Demon Prince appears before all rulers and powerful leaders telling them to join their cause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rituals begin unlocking keys, psychic energy siphoned to open portals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wuff, that&amp;rsquo;s a packed Danger for just one Front. You have two more to go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-dangers&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#more-dangers&#34;&gt;More Dangers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to making these Dangers feel connected is to ask or figure out how the goals of one Danger overlap with another. I choose to build a Danger first, then using that &lt;strong&gt;context&lt;/strong&gt; build the other Dangers so they either are working towards or against the big picture. Even if a Danger is working against another, someone is getting the short end of the deal and needs saving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;putting-this-together&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#putting-this-together&#34;&gt;Putting this together&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determine a starting location that makes sense or is agreed upon by the group. This could be the tavern, coming in from sea, or traveling through. Maybe a Red Star Cult fiasco happens in a local settlement festival, you pick. The main key is to get out there in the wilderness and explore. You&amp;rsquo;ll uncover other Grim Portents from the other Dangers if you have more than one. The players then are responsible for figuring out which Grim Portents are related and resolve the Danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Wilderness Roll defined above from Mythic Bastionland, we can keep &amp;ldquo;the story&amp;rdquo; front and center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your players do find that they&amp;rsquo;re a bit lost, tell them to talk to locals, seek knowledgeable people of the local area and get clues or rumors to guide them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-example-usage&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#an-example-usage&#34;&gt;An Example Usage!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;front-setup&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#front-setup&#34;&gt;Front Setup&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;front-1-details&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#front-1-details&#34;&gt;Front 1 Details&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front 1&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: The Pestilence Demon Xorosh corrupted the mind of the Lead Scientist Henry and gave him a false power to enhance humanoids. However, this power then lead to a beacon to be seen for a void-faring species to navigate to this realm, and crash land, taking root.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cast&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pestilence Demon, Xorosh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead Scientist Henry Johansen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xenothrax, the queen of hordes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stakes&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens if the region&amp;rsquo;s capitol is lost to the Hordes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do people try to sway the ultra-humanoids to find peace and join normal people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a way to find where these hordes came from in the void?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danger 1&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Planar Forces&lt;/em&gt; - Interstellar Being
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impulse&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;To force a mutation upon the world&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impending Doom&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Pestilence&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A shooting star is scene rocketing across the sky. Shards fall to the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animals start acting rabid and unusual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crops start dying to blight, people start getting sick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rulers start torching and burning infected sites and quarantine zones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutated abominations gather in the deep woods or dark caves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A master mind mutant leads hordes of mutations to attack large settlements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danger 2&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Ambitious Organizations&lt;/em&gt; - Biological Supremacy cult
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impulse&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;To use the gene code found to amplify a person&amp;rsquo;s core strengths&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impending Doom&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Usurpation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People heading to a crash/impact site of a meteor for its resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A group of young people are found leaping over tall buildings in a single bound. A group of people seem to be watching them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rumors of a ultra-humanoid are heard and sights of bands of ultra-strong people are seen bullying other normal people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settlement is decimated by a band of ultra-humanoids who were &amp;ldquo;settling a dispute&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Supreme Leader rises that unifies the roaming bands, local authorities are not pleased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ultra-humanoids decide that unmodified persons should be removed due to weakness and attack a local settlement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danger 3&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Hordes&lt;/em&gt; - Interstellar
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impulse&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Wreak havoc on the country side&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impending Doom&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Destruction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local fields and grounds are upturned as smaller vanguards are found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Hunter&amp;rsquo;s Lodge sets out to find the largest of the vermin. That should stop them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunter Forms are found stalking the edges of the forest, seemingly protecting something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hordes are seen heading towards the capitol settlement! There are so many of them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Hunter Lodges move to invade the forest nest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Queen moves, seeking a new nesting ground, the capitol underbelly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;front-2-details&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#front-2-details&#34;&gt;Front 2 Details&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front 2&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: The Demon Prince Barlon is wanting to open the gates of Hell by using followers of the the Red Star Cult to find keys and locks scattered through the realm. The Red Star Cult believes these will open a gateway to other realms to escape to. If the locks are opened, psychically attuned people will be gateways to allow demons through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cast&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demon Prince Barlon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Star Cult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citizens of the Region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stakes&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to the citizenry of the Region when demons flood the area?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the psychic people feel this presence or activity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the corruption look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danger 1&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Planar Forces&lt;/em&gt; - Demon Prince.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impulse&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Open gates of Hell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impending Doom&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Usurpation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSC raids local library and arcane college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychics begin turning ill and hospitals are flooded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creatures from long forgotten times terrorize country side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settlements are being uprooted and migrating to safe havens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Demon Prince appears before all rulers and powerful leaders telling them to join their cause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rituals begin unlocking keys, psychic energy siphoned to open portals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danger 2&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Hordes&lt;/em&gt; - Wandering Barbarians
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impulse&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;To grow strong, to drive their enemies before them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impending Doom&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Impoverishment&lt;/em&gt; (enslavement, the abandonment of goodness and right).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Livestock and animals have been released or stolen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Village left burned to the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pack of beast riders attack!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lines of captured people lead by barbarian riders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scorched grounds and barbarian encampments built near population centers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The barbarians invade/storm the capital burning and wreaking havoc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danger 3&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Cursed Places&lt;/em&gt; - Abandoned Tower
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impulse&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;To draw in the weak-willed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impending Doom&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Tyranny&lt;/em&gt; (of the strong over the weak or the few over the many).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grim Portents&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aetheric-sensitive individuals feel static everywhere they go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rampant growth of shrubbery and carnivorous vines start spreading outward from the Tower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People disappearing from their homes, others seeking their lost friends/family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large beasts spewing out of the area of the Tower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flying creatures spread miasma throughout the land.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The skies darken and the air becomes hard to breath, choking sunlight and life out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-map&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#the-map&#34;&gt;The Map&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the map first. If you read through Mythic Bastionland&amp;rsquo;s Realm Creation guidelines, you&amp;rsquo;ll see some similarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/images/dw-fronts-as-mb-wilderness-rolls.png&#34; alt=&#34;A 12x12 map for exploring using Mythic Bastionland&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly followed the Realm building guidelines from Mythic Bastionland, but for the sake of this example, I only included settlements, and the Danger locations. These &amp;ldquo;danger locations&amp;rdquo; are labeled 1-6 and should correspond top-down with the Dangers from the Fronts in order. With the map seeded, and our Fronts ready to go, let&amp;rsquo;s get exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lets-get-exploring&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#lets-get-exploring&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get exploring!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll start our group out at the top-most Settlement or Holding, 05.02. From here, we&amp;rsquo;ve talked to the locals and guard forces of the settlement to get a lead on a Danger in the area. So, we&amp;rsquo;ll head eastward towards 06.02. Now we&amp;rsquo;ll roll a 1d6 and see what our results are. I rolled a 5 on the die. No encounter here, so we keep traveling. We&amp;rsquo;ll go to 07.02 as our final stop for the day, as per the Mythic Bastionland Travel guidelines. This way we can rest in a settlement. Again, we roll 1d6. This time we rolled a 1, oh no! This time we roll for a random &lt;del&gt;Myth&lt;/del&gt; Danger and encounter the first &lt;del&gt;Omen&lt;/del&gt; Grim Portent. I roll a 4, this means that we count down the list of examples and end up on Front 2 - Danger 1, The Demon Prince!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now we encounter the first Grim Portent. It says that the Red Star Cult raids the local library and arcane college. This is where we take several liberties. We didn&amp;rsquo;t place the library or college in our prep. So, now we can say that it could be in this village. Why? Because the Holding said that the college could not be in the city walls for safety. Now, we have this context setup, and our PCs can choose to interact with the encounter, or leave it be. However, now this Danger has progressed its first Grim Portent. If/when this Danger&amp;rsquo;s Grim Portents reach the last step, the Danger &amp;ldquo;resolves&amp;rdquo; and the PCs must resolve that Danger where ever they are. But, what if we&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of the water? Well, use discretion as a GM, and remix the encounter so it fits, or in the next logical place it could be, such as where the PCs are heading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of if your PCs engaged or not, we&amp;rsquo;ll keep traveling eastward to find more information. The group moves into 08.02, and rolls another Wilderness Roll. This time we rolled a 6, it&amp;rsquo;s a quiet phase! The group moves forward another hex into 09.03 to avoid the watery terrain. This time on their Wilderness Roll, they roll a 3. We choose the closet Danger and encounter that Grim Portent. In this case, we&amp;rsquo;re closer to Front 1 - Danger 2, The Experiments! People are heading to a meteor crash site? Well, we can now say that there is a meteor crash site near by. Let&amp;rsquo;s ask the dice, &amp;ldquo;Is the crash site in this hex or the Danger&amp;rsquo;s Hex?&amp;rdquo; If I roll 1-3, current hex, 4-6, Danger hex. I roll a 5, so we&amp;rsquo;ve got a bit, and a few people heading eastward with us. They ask to travel with the party and seek safety in numbers. The PCs should at this point ask the NPCs where they&amp;rsquo;re heading, then follow them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the information the PCs gathered, they head into hex 10.03 and automatically encounter the next Grim Portent of the Danger in this hex. The next danger is Front 1 - Danger 2, a group of young people are seen leaping over tall buildings? Well, we&amp;rsquo;re in a crash site, so what do we do? Well, using our executive powers as GM, we could say that there was a dwelling here and the meteor crashed into it, or the young people are playing at the crash site. Either way, the Grim Portent is encountered. If the PCs continue to hang out in this hex and explore it, they will eventually uncover the other Grim Portents and resolve the danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-did-we-do-here&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#what-did-we-do-here&#34;&gt;What did we do here?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the ideas of Mythic Bastionland and the Fronts design of Dungeon World, we now have a few threads of related story to investigate by exploring the given map. Using rumors talking from NPCs or exploring blindly in the wilderness, the PCs will encounter various Grim Portents. It is up to the PCs to investigate certain Dangers&amp;rsquo; threads and resolve those by narrowing down the closeness of the encounters or by talking to local residents. Once the PCs find the Danger, they should know it because you didn&amp;rsquo;t roll! You could choose to roll, ignore the result and encounter the next Grim Portent, but then, you&amp;rsquo;re not playing by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bastionland.com/2018/09/the-ici-doctrine-information-choice.html&#34;&gt;ICI Doctrine&lt;/a&gt; and rolling in the open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#closing&#34;&gt;Closing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is a helpful idea or look at how to combine two tools together to build a narrative traveling adventure that is still sandbox and yet guide railed so the players feel they&amp;rsquo;re not just doing disconnected quests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources-of-inspiration&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/using-mythic-bastionland-with-dungeon-world/#sources-of-inspiration&#34;&gt;Sources of inspiration&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/mbplaytest&#34;&gt;Mythic Bastionland&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bastionland.com/&#34;&gt;Bastionland Press&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dungeon-world.com/&#34;&gt;Dungeon World&lt;/a&gt; by Sage Kobold Productions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dungeonworldsrd.com/&#34;&gt;System Reference Document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Game-Masters-Handbook-Proactive-Roleplaying/dp/1956403442&#34;&gt;The Game Master&amp;rsquo;s Handbook to Proactive Roleplaying&lt;/a&gt; by Topic Media Lab. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/en/product/463026/the-game-master-s-handbook-of-proactive-roleplaying&#34;&gt;DriveThruRPG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Rolemaster Unified Characters</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 17:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally went through and created a Rolemaster character from scratch by reading the book and not using the ERA or having someone else help me do it. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to provide bullet point lists and page references with parts of the sheet I did. Hopefully this will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find Rolemaster to be a supremely rewarding role-playing game because you literally can do anything you want, given time and resources poured into skills. A fighter could learn to cast spells, and a spell caster can learn to perform arts. However, the scary part of Rolemaster is the up front character builder options and decisions to make. This looks imposing as the character sheet is near tax form level, but once you get your initial build down, and a couple advancements, you&amp;rsquo;ll be chucking dice real fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other neat things about Rolemaster is that the Critical Tables in the Arms Law are fun to use in any other role-playing game and the Spell Law is usable as well as is with nearly any game. It&amp;rsquo;s real neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here on out, I&amp;rsquo;ll be referring to Rolemaster Unified as &lt;code&gt;RMU&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-build-supplies&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#pre-build-supplies&#34;&gt;Pre-build Supplies&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before jumping into your character build, players should have the following supplies ready to build the PC and record any purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grid Graph Paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pencil with eraser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One to three sets of d100 dice.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One is a 1-0, and the other is 10-00.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character Sheet(s)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or two copies of the character sheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that can make this helpful is pre-filling out the skills sheets with the various Profession advancement costs and professional skills already marked. However, this would depend on your GM or the community to provide something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could totally use a digital tool like Obsidian, Notion, LogSeq, or JoplinApp to do the character creation record as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rmu-build-process&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#rmu-build-process&#34;&gt;RMU Build Process&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power-level&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#power-level&#34;&gt;Power Level&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.244-245 - Section 12.1 Power Levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of this explanation I use the &lt;code&gt;Superior&lt;/code&gt; Power Level, which is one step above Average. A GM or the Players may want to do more of a Heroic pulpy game or a more higher level game. Discuss this before hand. The default assumptions seem to be Superior. In my opinion, you have room to grow for longer games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Power Level also impacts starting stats, skill bonuses, talents, and magic. I would say to try a Superior game first, then see about starting at higher levels as desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-concept&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#character-concept&#34;&gt;Character Concept&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.18-20 - Section 2.1 Background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because RMU is a &amp;ldquo;generic fantasy&amp;rdquo; game, and is flexible with how characters are built, just like GURPS, HERO System, Basic Roleplaying, or Genesys, it is important to have a character concept to build and lean into. Other games use classes to provide a pre-planned progression path. So, take sometime, talk with the GM and understand the setting. If you&amp;rsquo;re playing solo, generate your setting, and then build your PC to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something to do will be to look over the &lt;em&gt;Races&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cultures&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Professions&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Talents&lt;/em&gt; to help inform what is available, unless your GM is making custom elements of their game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-race&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#character-race&#34;&gt;Character Race&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.20-49 - Section 2.2 Races.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.21 - Table 2-2a Races&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.48 - Table 2-2b Race Sizes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This choice will be based upon your character concept. Your character concept is probably informed by this choice as well. The information on the tables are useful for those who know what they want and where to put the data. For those who are shopping around, or are new to the game, the pages between are useful for learning more about the implied setting and tone of RMU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first build, I&amp;rsquo;m choosing a &lt;code&gt;Human, Common&lt;/code&gt; since it is fairly easy to work with as the only notable thing that this race gets is extra Development Points or DP. The Race Sizes table isn&amp;rsquo;t real useful for me, but it is nice to have to fill in and give yourself some reference points to imagine the size and form of your character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-culture&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#character-culture&#34;&gt;Character Culture&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.49-52 - Section 2.3 Culture.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.51 - Table 2-3 Cultures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Race is what you&amp;rsquo;re character was born as, but Culture is what your character grew up doing before taking on the mantle of adventurer. The table on p.51 is useful for quickly assigning Ranks to your Skills, but reading each Culture has some extra Skills suggested for skills that have multiple specializations. Of course, you&amp;rsquo;re free to do whatever you want that you think fits in your Culture&amp;rsquo;s tropes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to read p.49 because it details some good information about Lore Skills and Language Skill. Language Skills are split between Spoken and Written ranks. The languages available are defined as part of the setting you&amp;rsquo;re playing in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-professions&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#character-professions&#34;&gt;Character Professions&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.53-70 - Section 2.4 Professions
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.58 - Table 2-4a Profession Skill Costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.59 - Table 2-4b Professional Skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is where we pick what our character will be good at. Ideally, this is defined in your character concept and informed a bit by your Culture. However, you&amp;rsquo;re free to deviate and be weird, because we all do it in our lives. The tables listed yet again provide quick build access for those who know what they want, but each Profession has a detail section, Professional Skills, and the Skill Category Costs for this profession. Later on when purchasing skills, leaning into these Professional Skills listed will help define and give your character niches to work within for the rest of the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also get to give a 1 Bonus distributed among 10 Professional Skills. This bonus is equal to number of ranks in the skill, up to a max of 30. Make sure read the examples on RMU Core Law p.53!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then pick 2 more skills, and give those a +5 Knack bonus. This is not a rank, but just a +5 bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generating-character-stats&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#generating-character-stats&#34;&gt;Generating character stats&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.70-73 - Section 2.5 Stats.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.71 - Table 2-5a Stat Bonuses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the initial meat of the character. Roll d100 three times, taking the highest for Potential Stat, middle for Temporary Stat, and discard the lowest. If any of the stat rolls are 11 or lower, re-roll that stat roll until you get a value higher. Depending on power level, this minimum value may change. Make sure to follow the steps and recommendations on p.72 for generating and raising low stats. These stats are important later in the skills portion, but any low skills can have their temporary rating raised to their potential rating. High potential ratings mean that the character has the chance to get better if their temporary stat is low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stat Bonuses are calculated based off of the Temporary Stat Score. This is important as your character progresses in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-skills&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#character-skills&#34;&gt;Character Skills&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.73-74 - Section 2.6 Skills &amp;amp; Talents, 82-112 - Chapter 3 Skills.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.82 - Table 3-0a Skill Summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.84 - Table 3-0b Skill Ranks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see by the large page count in the Skills chapter, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of important. Characters start with 60 DP plus any Racial DP as well. I interpret the spending as, your character gets 60+(Race DP Bonus), but you can only use up to 25 of your Racial DP until entirely spent. So for a Common Human with 50 extra DP, this means that they would get 85 DP for the first two levels to help give them a bit of a boost in life. After that, they&amp;rsquo;re at the same 60 DP like everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filling in your skills is important as ranks in certain skills inform other parts of your character such as Basic Movement Rate, Hit Points, Defensive Bonus, and Offensive Bonus, plus a few others. Skills cost a number of DP per Rank when improving. These usually have two numbers listed, the first is the first rank&amp;rsquo;s cost, the second is the second rank&amp;rsquo;s cost. The way I read this is that if you only have two numbers listed, you can only buy ranks twice per advancement. I recommend leaning into your Professional Skills first until you&amp;rsquo;ve bought 2 ranks in each. Then you can get into what I call &amp;ldquo;hobby skills&amp;rdquo; or things your character may have picked up along the way in their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the Skill Category&amp;rsquo;s Bonuses by using the Stat Bonuses listed. Then for each skill, fill in the default score. Some of them may be positive, some may be negative. It&amp;rsquo;s okay! You&amp;rsquo;ll have chances to grow out of these negatives and offset those by putting ranks in those skills. As noted on p.83, any skill that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a rank associated with it starts at a -25 bonus to any rolls. These are offset by Stat Bonuses, or by Culture Skill Ranks. Rank vs Score or Bonus mean different things. Ranks use the Skill Ranks table on p.84 to calculate the bonus, and Bonus or Score simply add the value to the end result Skill Bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some skills will have specializations. Work with the GM to define the Lores, Languages, and if your crafts, vocations, and other specializations are relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spells, Power Skills, and other magic related skills have a different way to figure out their skill bonuses, but that&amp;rsquo;s covered in RMU Spell Law. (see further on in the article for more information).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-talents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#character-talents&#34;&gt;Character Talents&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.114-122 - Chapter 4 Talents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IF you have extra DP to spend, and it fits your character concept, and the GM allows it, your starting character may purchase a Talent or few. These are boons and banes to your character. Boons cost DP, and Banes give you back DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t focus too much on Talents during my character creations, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much in the way of experience or advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-touches&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#finishing-touches&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Finishing Touches&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is a bit of a lie, because you&amp;rsquo;ll have to buy gear, hop around and fill in other spots, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a cop out of providing an entire comprehensive list or how-to when doing character creation. So, that means we need to read more of the book carefully in order to fill in various other spots on our character sheet. However, that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;basic-movement-rate&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#basic-movement-rate&#34;&gt;Basic Movement Rate&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches, p.128 - Section 5.3 Movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BMR is defaulted at 20 feet plus half Quickness Bonus rounded-up and modified by Stride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hit-points&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#hit-points&#34;&gt;Hit Points&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hits are equal to the character&amp;rsquo;s Racial base plus Body Development Skill Bonus. Then modify based upon the character size if not medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;defensive-bonus&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#defensive-bonus&#34;&gt;Defensive Bonus&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Defensive Bonus, DB, is equal to 3x Quickness Stat Bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;endurance&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#endurance&#34;&gt;Endurance&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches, p.129-130 - Section 5.5 Fatigue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encumbrance is equal to Body Development Skill Bonus plus endurance modifier for the character&amp;rsquo;s race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;encumbrance&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#encumbrance&#34;&gt;Encumbrance&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches, p.128-129 - Section 5.4 Encumbrance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.134-149 - Chapter 6 Equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characters start with a certain amount of Silver, sp, as listed in Table 6-0a Starting Money. My character was Poor, so they started with 10sp. This was enough to buy somethings, but there were in debt a little bit by the end. All the more reason to go adventuring. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it&amp;rsquo;s 10sp per level when I&amp;rsquo;m starting at level 1, but I suppose this is if you&amp;rsquo;re starting at a higher level than just 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, a nice GM would create a &amp;ldquo;starting pack&amp;rdquo; or some sort to get characters going. This could also be part of a benefactor that the characters work for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;gear&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#gear&#34;&gt;Gear&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.137-139 - Table 6-3 General Equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;weapons&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#weapons&#34;&gt;Weapons&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.141-142 - Table 6-5 Weapons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weapons do not provide Offensive Bonuses, that is based upon your Skill Bonus for the listed type of weapon. The weapon then is given a specialization category that enables the character to better wield the weapon. When attacking, the weapon&amp;rsquo;s Attack defines the Attack Table to use when resolving combat. This could be a melee weapon, ranged weapon, or if using simple Magic or Spell Law, spells as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;armor&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#armor&#34;&gt;Armor&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.140 - Table 6-4 Armor and Shields, p.148 - Table 7-2b Armor Types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armor doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily provide Defensive Bonuses, only shields do. What Armor does is provide an Armor Type, AT, that then informs Attack Tables how many hits and if a Critical Hit is achieved. Higher AT&amp;rsquo;s may get hit more, but they don&amp;rsquo;t crit as much, where lower ATs may get hit, but may crit a lot sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;initiative&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#initiative&#34;&gt;Initiative&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initiative bonus is equal to Quickness Stat Bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;power-points&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#power-points&#34;&gt;Power Points&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power Points, PP, is equal to the character&amp;rsquo;s Power Development Skill Bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;resistance-rolls&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#resistance-rolls&#34;&gt;Resistance Rolls&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RMU Core Law p.74 - Section 2.7 Finishing Touches, p.131-132 - Section 5.6 Resistance Rolls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 5 Resistances. Each are based on a Stat Bonus, Level, Race and anything special. You get +2 per level, and +10 for resistance to magic of your own realm, like Essence, Arcane, Mentalism and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-little-gotchas&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#other-little-gotchas&#34;&gt;Other little gotchas&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things I had a rough time figuring out without reading each page and scrutinizing all the tables were things like Passive Dodge, or Passive Block. These are listed in &lt;code&gt;RMU Core Law&#39;s Arms Law p.167 - Table 9-5 The Attack Roll&lt;/code&gt;. Here, players would go down the table adding or subtracting values from the final roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive Block is +1 DB per Shield Rank, where a Full Block is just the Shield Skill Bonus. Passive Dodge is +1 DB per Movement Skill Rank, and a Full Dodge is the specific Movement Skill Bonus. Which movement skill? That depends on how you&amp;rsquo;re moving and whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re doing a run by, swim, climb or fly by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else on the character sheet first page is pretty self-explanatory where it provides the formulas to determine the values that go in there. These may be adjusted as characters advance and stats and skills go up or down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-to-start-play&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#time-to-start-play&#34;&gt;Time to start play&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woof. Well, now that we&amp;rsquo;ve done all this, the rest of the game is simple. Roll percentile dice, add your Skill Bonus, and attempt to roll higher than the Maneuver Chart on &lt;code&gt;RMU Core Law p.125 - Table 5-1 Maneuvers&lt;/code&gt;. If attacking, Roll the same as a Maneuver, but subtract the defender&amp;rsquo;s DB and then consult the Attack Tables in the RMU Arms Law section. The game is really simple, it&amp;rsquo;s just character initialization that is daunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you play, and ask questions, the GM will make rulings as any other role-playing game, but after the session, the GM and Players should consult the various rule books and see if they can figure out if there is a defined rule for the situation in question. If there is not, make a ruling, write it down, and you&amp;rsquo;ve become a game designer. These home rules will most likely need tweaking, but try to not get hung up on exactness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;magic-users-and-spell-lists&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#magic-users-and-spell-lists&#34;&gt;Magic Users and Spell Lists&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;re really raring to play a Spell Caster of some sort. There are a few realms of spell casting in RMU. There is: Channeling, Essence, and Mentalism. Each of these have Base, Open, Closed, and Restricted Spell Lists. I believe there is also an Arcane realm, but that&amp;rsquo;s a bit different. On the character sheet, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice &lt;code&gt;RS+RS+ME&lt;/code&gt;, this is RS == Realm Stat. The Realm Stat can be found in &lt;code&gt;RMU Spell Law p.15 - Section 2.2 Realms of Magic&lt;/code&gt;. For Channeling, this is Intuition (In) stat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spell-lists-and-skills&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#spell-lists-and-skills&#34;&gt;Spell Lists and Skills&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spell Lists are chosen as Skills when choosing a Profession.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each Skill Rank in a chosen Spell List lets the caster cast spells of the same Rank/Level.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Skill Ranks in Concussion&amp;rsquo;s Ways means the caster can cast Light Exposure Relief.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the playground for the magically minded player. So many choices. Depending on the amount of DP you have in the beginning and whether or not you buy any talents, you may need to start with one or two spell lists with at least one or skill ranks per Spell List. This would enable the spell caster to be more useful as they&amp;rsquo;re primarily focusing on their magic. Again, you can focus on whatever you want to develop character skill wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/making-rmu-characters/#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of a misnomer, but these are some thoughts I have after doing this process twice, and learning more about the character generation. While the vast array of character sheets seem daunting and overwhelming, the majority of them are not used until you start investing development points into the various skills or getting magical items and gear. This means to me that most of the daunting work is in the actual character initialization and concept crafting. Professional Skills are there to help guide you in what you should specialize in, but youre free to do whatever you want as compared to other games that bind you to one or two classes. The actual game play is fairly easy and quick to get going. Actual game play will come later on in another post once I get a few solo sessions in before getting players at the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If youre still flabbergasted, there is something called an ERA or Electronic Roleplay Assistant, for Rolemaster. You need to buy the ERA and the various source material, but then creating characters is a snap in the program. However, I did find it more confusing trying to use the ERA before doing a couple manual character builds. Do the hard thing first, then the easy stuff will make more sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic Dungeon Generation</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while, I had many people tell me to try using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sersavictory.itch.io/cyclic-dungeon-generation&#34;&gt;Cyclic Dungeon
Generation&lt;/a&gt; method as
found and detailed on itch.io by Sersa Victory. For a while, I would read the
document and get confused on how to envision the end result or how the dungeon
worked. What I am going to show is not the BE ALL END ALL method, as this
probably work differently for other people. So, I will show some images,
describe the cycles drawn, and then how I pieced it together to get a final
result. The book Cyclic Dungeon Generation has a wonderful walk through and an
example dungeon using that result. I suggest reading it once or twice, then also
trying to do your own while following the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-youll-need&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#things-youll-need&#34;&gt;Things you&amp;rsquo;ll need&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index Cards 3x5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marker or Pencil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;drawing-cycles&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#drawing-cycles&#34;&gt;Drawing Cycles?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep. I made some cards to draw cycles instead of rolling them. One because I had
a deck of blank cards to work with, and cards are fun sometimes. Here&amp;rsquo;s what
they look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/images/CDG-Cycles-Cards.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image of Cyclic Dungeon cycles on
cards&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all found in the book originally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I followed the tutorial on Page 6-7. I drew the first cycle, then at the
first two insertion points, I drew two other cycles. I felt that was enough to
start with to get the feel for doing this manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-complete-cycle-flowchart&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#the-complete-cycle-flowchart&#34;&gt;The complete cycle flowchart&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I drew my cards for the cycles, I wrote them on a piece of paper and drew
it as demonstrated in the book. I drew Cycle 11, Cycle 10, and Cycle 03.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/images/CDG-01-Flowchart.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The initial flowchart of my Cyclic
Dungeon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still a little hard to mentally visualize for me as I know I&amp;rsquo;m going in
a circle, but the start is over there? Then where is the goal? How do I go back?
Hopefully visually mapping it helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mapping-the-first-cycle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#mapping-the-first-cycle&#34;&gt;Mapping the first cycle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took my index cards and tore them in half (or cut them if you&amp;rsquo;re fancy). I
then wrote down the words as shown on my cycle flowchart. I then laid the card
halves out as shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/images/CDG-02-Initial-Cycle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Initial cycle diagram made out of index
cards&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works for me, and helps me get the initial flow down. What is hard to do
whend drawing on paper or using digital tools is knowing that the initial
cycle&amp;rsquo;s goal gets stretched out as you insert more cycles. So, let&amp;rsquo;s insert a
second cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inserting-the-second-cycle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#inserting-the-second-cycle&#34;&gt;Inserting the second cycle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;ll insert a second cycle. For this, I chose the bottom one with the
secret path to our key. So, I moved the Goal back, and replaced Insert Point
with the cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/images/CDG-03-Including-Second-Cycle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The second cycle insertion with a hidden
path&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to rotate the cycle as well so that the start made sense, and the two
insertion points we&amp;rsquo;re not using get turned into extra rooms for encounters or
breather rooms. Here, you should see the loop where the key is and kind of
visualize where the logical flow of the dungeon goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inserting-our-final-cycle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#inserting-our-final-cycle&#34;&gt;Inserting our final cycle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our final (second) cycle, I took the cards and elongated the cycle making it
a line instead. To me it made more sense to do this. In the final result you&amp;rsquo;ll
see kind of what I was thinking and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/images/CDG-04-Full-Cycle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The third cycle insertion with a false
goal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycle had the &amp;ldquo;true goal&amp;rdquo; which was really just editing the cycle in this
case, but if it were the key insertion point, then the true goal would&amp;rsquo;ve been
the key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-results&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#final-results&#34;&gt;Final Results&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I laid out the index cards and maneuvered them so that they made sense on
my table, I then drew this on paper. Some liberties were taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/images/CDG-05-End-Result.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The final result
dungeon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll see the the entry point, then we go to the left, following the hallway
and are presented with our first &amp;ldquo;False Goal&amp;rdquo;. After I drew this, did the
hatching, I realized I should&amp;rsquo;ve made the false goal room similar to the actual
goal room and then have a surprise, or something. Live and you learn. Then you
make your way down two more rooms that may have encounters or lore spouts. The
final boss, BUT, the doors are locked, so we need the key! Our adventurers then
would need to traverse the halls more, and either percept the hidden path or
traverse the other two rooms and then perform some sort of task to get the key.
I would also then show the hidden path as a viable route similar to Skyrim
showing that the Players should always search or just as a repreive from having
to go all the way around. Thenn they can go back and unlock the boss doors, and
let the murdering ensue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/cyclic-dungeon-generation/#final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do enjoy the Cyclic Dungeon Generation method. It was a little abstract for me
at the onset because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought about dungeons in this way even though I
had seen them in other video games like Dark Souls, Legend of Zelda, and many
others. Doing this manual large blown out way helped me to visually identify
what it was actually doing and then draw it. I also found it a little easier
than doing this in a drawing tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://excalidraw.com&#34;&gt;Excalidraw&lt;/a&gt;. Go
pick up the book, read it out loud to yourself so you see, say, and hear it and
then practice the cycle method. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyhedral Prep</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to explain how I&amp;rsquo;m using &amp;ldquo;polyhedral frames&amp;rdquo; as I&amp;rsquo;ve been
calling them to prepare adventure locations, battle maps, and space sectors
and what not. This is not an original concept, but I took the &amp;ldquo;Site Preparation&amp;rdquo;
from &lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/mbplaytest&#34;&gt;Mythic Bastionland&lt;/a&gt; and expand upon it a bit to
give more variation and feel for various locations. In Mythic Bastionland, Chris
shows how to use a &amp;ldquo;Hex&amp;rdquo; to build a Site, or anything to be explored. This to me
stood out as a d6 on its side showing the point at you. So, I decided to use
other role-playing dice polyhedrals. You&amp;rsquo;ll see the frames further down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-polyhedral-prep&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/#what-is-polyhedral-prep&#34;&gt;What is Polyhedral Prep?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the term: Polyhedral Prep, because I saw RPG Dice called Polyhedrals, so
it stuck. After having these frames I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do next with them. It
wasn&amp;rsquo;t until reading Mythic Bastionland and Electric Bastionland that I came to
the conclusion I could use these as a sort of &amp;ldquo;dungeon madlib&amp;rdquo; by giving each
vertex a location and each connection or line an encounter; very much like
Electric Bastionland Boroughs. So, I numbered each vertex and line/connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/images/Polyhedral_Frames.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image of Dice Polyhedrals with vertices and connections
numbered.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-this-method&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/#how-do-i-use-this-method&#34;&gt;How do I use this method?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll be defining a small Site, or dungeon using the d6 frame.
Using the guidelines from Mythic Bastionland, we define an entrance and a couple
open pathways, one or two closed paths and a secret path. Each vertex then gets
a keyword pair. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to use an Oracle Descriptor Table like the ones
found in Mythic Game Master Emulator Second Edition or Ironsworn Starforged
(Ironsworn doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a description oracle). Locations get descriptors that
fit within the context of the site. So if it is a dungeon and we roll something
like: Haunted/Outpost, it seems pretty inspiring so far. Haunted, maybe this
dungeon is loaded full of spirits. Outpost in a dungeon, that could be a lookout
room or tower. Maybe this is a fort full of spirits of soldiers that man the
ramparts. Bam, we have our first location in the site. Now we repeat the process
for each vertex staying within context. Make sure to use your other previous
locations in the site to inform how you interpret and make the rest of the
locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do a connection or encounter. For this we&amp;rsquo;ll want an action site as we
need to interact with the PCs instead of them interacting with the location.
Think active versus passive. So, we&amp;rsquo;ll roll: Seize/Superstition. My first
thought is to think of how I can make this an active encounter to engage the PC.
How do I seize? Could be a grab trap, could be someone trying to steal my soul,
or something. We could also do seize of breath because of fear. Maybe, when the
PCs go down connection/encounter (1), they see an apparition of the boss spirit
of the Site, quick all PCs make a WIS Save! Any that fail, then have
disadvantage on checks and must make the check again when facing the BBEG later
one. Bam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then repeat this process for each location (vertex) and each encounter
(connection). Make sure you spread out a few locations with loot or lore as well
and not just encounters. Something else I do is add an NPC per location if it&amp;rsquo;s
a populated location that isn&amp;rsquo;t immediately hostile for the PCs to talk to. If
it&amp;rsquo;s a hostile Site, just key the room as you would a traditional dungeon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/polyhedral-prep/#an-example&#34;&gt;An example!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example from a game I ran a while ago where the players were
investigating an asteroid mining station looking for a missing individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/journal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An A5 Journal Spread of polyhedral prep notes.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/polyhedral-on-trace-paper.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/belter-station.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/icrpg-sector-map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/polyhedral-dungeon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing Up Binary Pass Fail</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/changing-up-binary-pass-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 01:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/changing-up-binary-pass-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/changing-up-binary-pass-fail/#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking on this after discussing it with some people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to
play certain games like Genesys or even Powered by the Apocalypse. Why? I can
only guess at it. However, I also wanted to think on how to allowing people to
continue playing with their standard binary pass-fail results, but enable those
who want to negotiate or barter their rolls so they can do cool stuff
narratively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;binary-pass-fail&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/changing-up-binary-pass-fail/#binary-pass-fail&#34;&gt;Binary Pass-Fail&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my take on it, but binary pass-fail is simply, you pass or you fail.
When you roll a check, regardless of how many dice you roll or what kinds you
roll, the easiest idea is simply a coin flip. You either meet or beat the target
number and you pass or you fail. You do or you don&amp;rsquo;t. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Does this seem
pretty limiting? For ease of use and simplicity, it&amp;rsquo;s great. However, let&amp;rsquo;s take
a look at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take note, I would reward a player describing what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, even if they
don&amp;rsquo;t know or have no idea what they would do, as long as they work with the
GM&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your player is engaged with a mystery investigation and they&amp;rsquo;re searching
through a suspect&amp;rsquo;s house looking for something. That player then describes
they&amp;rsquo;re looking here, and there; behind picture frames, and attempting to move
the rug under the coffee table. Maybe a roll for the coffee table, but if that
is successful, then they go through all of that, and then they look at the GM
and the GM says, &amp;ldquo;Roll investigation&amp;rdquo;. That player chucks the dice, rolls a 2,
and then you as the GM say, &amp;ldquo;You fail to find anything&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, maybe there is not anything there and player just wasted all their time.
Maybe the suspect has hid the evidence in a place the player didn&amp;rsquo;t describe.
Either way, these also both violate things called &lt;code&gt;The ICI Doctrine&lt;/code&gt; by Chris
MacDowall. The first assumption, they wasted their time. With the ICI Doctrine,
the GM should&amp;rsquo;ve stopped the player and say, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing of interest here.
The next thing the GM could&amp;rsquo;ve done was wait until after all of that work and
say, &amp;ldquo;You find nothing&amp;rdquo; because they spent all the time searching. BUT, we&amp;rsquo;re
here to discuss that die roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-we-do-to-help-that&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/changing-up-binary-pass-fail/#what-can-we-do-to-help-that&#34;&gt;What can we do to help that?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the GM knows that there is something in the suspect&amp;rsquo;s house, then what I am
proposing is a &amp;ldquo;fail-forward&amp;rdquo; using a binary result. If the PC fails their
check, then the GM and/or the Player can barter for a success, but at a great
cost, or barter for a failure, but with a benefit. This opens up at least +2
more axis of results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may run the risk of being abused, but most mature, realistic gamers would
be good enough to know when to not to abuse this. It could also add extra time
to each turn if someone is just constantly eeking out little bonuses and such,
but then you&amp;rsquo;re also getting that in other games like FATE or PbtA already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I do think that this could help those who MUST make a roll in certain
situations that want that success, but at a cost, or realize they failed, but
get a boon to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/changing-up-binary-pass-fail/#tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of pass-fail rolls, allow bartering for success at a great cost or
fail for a boon in the story or setting up an advantage for someone else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Solo24</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/challenge-solo24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 21:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/challenge-solo24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/challenge-solo24/#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2023, Sean McCoy put out a challenge that each day, creators
create a room of a dungeon a day that builds into mega dungeon of sorts. Then
keep all of this in a journal for future use. This was called Dungeon23 for
2023. It&amp;rsquo;s a practice of patience and making sure to stick with something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to propose a challenge for 2024 called Solo24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/challenge-solo24/#resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seanmccoy.substack.com/p/dungeon23&#34;&gt;#dungeon23 | Sean McCoy (substack)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://monstersmazes.blogspot.com/2023/11/hexplore24.html&#34;&gt;#hexplore24 | Monsters &amp;amp; Mazes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solo24&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/challenge-solo24/#solo24&#34;&gt;Solo24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each day, play out a Scene building a Plot Point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each week constitutes a Turning Point in an Adventure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each month constitutes as an Adventure of 4 or 5 Turning Points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of the year, should have a Campaign consisting of 12 Adventures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick/Roll for a Genre and Setting and stick to this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to use different Themes and Tones for each Turning Point or Adventure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you fall behind and miss a day, do not try to catch up unless you want to.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will not build good habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goal(s) is/are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish something you start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to pace and end Scene, Adventure, Campaign.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful even for a Sandbox game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;random-genres&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/challenge-solo24/#random-genres&#34;&gt;Random Genres&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;dice: 1d6&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Genre&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Fantasy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Science Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Space Opera&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Post-Apocalypse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Weird West/Historical Fiction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Modern&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Play Impromptu Pbta</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I just wanna play a role-playing game at a restaurant while waiting
for food or when at the office. With the availability of 2d6 in most stores or
board games, or the power of a mobile device, dice are easy to come by. I
recently read and played &lt;em&gt;World of Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;FIST&lt;/em&gt; after re-reading Dungeon
World and struggling with Ironsworn initially. I had to learn how to GM, be a
player, then realize the kinds of games I liked while soloing. Doing this, I
realized that understanding the actionable intent of a character and the
obstacle present in the given context can help make a dice roll more dramatic or
not even needed. I still play Index Card RPG Master Edition, Worlds Without
Number, EZD6, Basic Roleplaying and other games, but Powered by the Apocalypse
had always intrigued me. I think after reading World of Dungeons and Simple
World, it finally clicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am presenting here isn&amp;rsquo;t a whole new game or anything but using the core
of PbtA to tell a story cooperatively based upon player action and their goals.
This is all thanks to Powered by the Apocalypse of Apocalypse World by Vincent
Baker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-a-character&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/#make-a-character&#34;&gt;Make a Character&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grab a napkin or index card and a pen or pencil and follow the steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define 3-6 Attributes.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example: Strength, Dexterity, Willpower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign 3 Points amongst the Attributes.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would stick with 3-6 points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generally the same number of points as the number of attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down 6 Wounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down 1 Background statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down 1 Profession statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down 1 Connection statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a setting is provided, the players may want to choose a goal. For impromptu
sessions this may be handled by the GM for the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rolling-dice&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/#rolling-dice&#34;&gt;Rolling Dice&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take 2d6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide which attribute to use.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the attribute points to the total of 2d6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If any statements about your character fit the situation, add +1 to the result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare against the Results Chart below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Roll 2d6&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Results&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Double-Ones*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Critical Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6 or less&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7-9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Partial Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 or higher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Full Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Double-Sixes*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Critical Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; - Optional results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-play&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/#how-to-play&#34;&gt;How to play&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GM defines the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Player states their character&amp;rsquo;s intention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GM and Player work out the success result and what failure would look like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roll the dice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If Full Success, the desired intent happens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If Partial Success, the desired intent happens but a complication happens as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If Failure, the action doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen and the opponent gets and advantage or action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s break down the cycle of operations listed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the Game Master (GM) defines the situation, the location, and any
opponents, challenges, or obstacles. This should be pretty bog standard for
anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been a GM or likes imagining this kind of stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a
paranormal mercenary mood recently with monstrous or strange entities. So, in
this situation the team of Player Characters (PCs) are working their way into
the basement of an ever changing layout corporate office building to retrieve an
anomalous artifact. However, there is a counter operative team working to secure
their research for corporate interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your team rounds the corner of the hallway, it opens into a conference room where you see a capsule made of glass and you see the artifact on a pedestal in the middle of the capsule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the Players state their intentions. These are usually defined as
&amp;ldquo;actions&amp;rdquo;. Most other games allow the PCs a move and an action. So, the player
states what they want their operative to do this round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell the team to cover me as I work my way to the capsule. Looking for traps and trip wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see laser trips at ankle height. Your character is proficient enough to know to step over them. However, as you&amp;rsquo;re approaching the capsule dodging the trip lasers, you see a counter op team. They open fire! &lt;em&gt;What do you do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I move to cover behind a pillar and return fire, allowing my team mates to move up to assist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this is where I think most people find difficult or challenging,
negotiation. The rules for combat aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly defined as something you&amp;rsquo;d find
in a tactical game where exact measurements are used. You certainly could, but
we&amp;rsquo;re impromptu. Let&amp;rsquo;s take into account the current Context of the scene: in a
conference room like a hotel or office building or library; then we&amp;rsquo;re dodging
the laser trips; then we&amp;rsquo;re being fired upon. So, the GM states this and a
possible complication for the player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so you&amp;rsquo;re returning fire at the group of operatives shooting at you. Roll 2d6 plus your DEX score to hit an inflict a wound to the group. If you get a Partial Success you&amp;rsquo;ll take a wound as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m behind cover, would we reduce that to a piece of equipment is broken? Maybe the enemies move positions too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, but you&amp;rsquo;ll act with a -1 penalty next round to any action without them moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll them bones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a contrite example and hard for some to conceptualize since they&amp;rsquo;re not
familiar with the expectations I&amp;rsquo;m leaning upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explain some more gamified specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-specifics&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/#game-specifics&#34;&gt;Game specifics&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damage&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;em&gt;flattened&lt;/em&gt; to be 1 wound per success when attacking. This could
also be negotiated to 2 wounds when getting a Critical Success or when the
attack narratively makes sense like using a grenade or close range shotgun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should always be a &lt;strong&gt;Complication&lt;/strong&gt; when performing an action. This helps
drive the &lt;em&gt;Partial Success&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Failure&lt;/em&gt;. If the GM doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what a
Complication for a given actionable intent is, they should look at the current
Context and use that, or if there isn&amp;rsquo;t a known complication, then there isn&amp;rsquo;t a
roll. If the players are willing, they can help provide contextual
complications. Not all groups are into this though, so mileage varies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weapons and Gear&lt;/strong&gt; aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily spelled out either. Since we&amp;rsquo;re
impromptu and narrative, it&amp;rsquo;s assumed you&amp;rsquo;re in possession of the gear you need.
If this were a longer term and planned out game session, I&amp;rsquo;d have a buying
system, meta currencies and a bunch of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example I didn&amp;rsquo;t specify or use a &lt;strong&gt;Statement&lt;/strong&gt; about the PC in the
scene. If the Player invoked one of their Statements, then they&amp;rsquo;d get to add a
+1 to their total results. These Statements also allow the PC to do things
special or have access to things other characters may not get. It might even
eliminate the need for a roll if the actionable intent is within the wheel
house. The only thing I&amp;rsquo;m going to put my feet down on is that you cannot skip
combat unless the Players and GM agree to doing an action like &amp;ldquo;Battle&amp;rdquo; where
the whole combat is handled in a single roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-i-want-a-d20&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/how-to-play-impromptu-pbta/#but-i-want-a-d20&#34;&gt;But, I want a d20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people have a strong &lt;del&gt;dependence&lt;/del&gt; preference for using a d20 instead of
2d6. Here&amp;rsquo;s the same resolution mechanic using a d20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Roll d20&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Results&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Natural 1*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Critical Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9 or less&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10-15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Partial Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Natural 20*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Critical Success&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Same Bonuses for the Attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe make Statement add +2 instead of +1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My D6 Oracle Table</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/my-d6-oracle-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/my-d6-oracle-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-d6-oracle-table&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/my-d6-oracle-table/#my-d6-oracle-table&#34;&gt;My D6 Oracle Table&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/my-d6-oracle-table/#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple oracle table that is admidtely using the values from Ironsworn,
and the &lt;code&gt;The No-Prep Gamemaster&lt;/code&gt; by Dicegeeks. It should be fairly simple. I use
this during my live sessions to cut down on the amount of cross-referencing of
tables and other things. Mythic Game Master Emulator&amp;rsquo;s Fate Chart is great for
solo games or prep sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-oracle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/my-d6-oracle-table/#the-oracle&#34;&gt;The Oracle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;dice: 1d6&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Oracle&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenario&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nope&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Worse Case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Almost Certain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Really Bad&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Likely&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bad&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50/50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Okay&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unlikely&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Good&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Small Chance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Best Case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A roll of 1 on the Oracle table is always a NOPE. Every other value is meet or
beat the value matching the odds of a Yes answer. The Scenario column adds
flavor to the result from the oracle. You may get a Yes answer, but it may not
be super favorable. Essentially, try to roll high on both columns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use The Adventure Crafter With Microscope</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 02:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-ya-babblin-about&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#what-are-ya-babblin-about&#34;&gt;What are ya babblin&amp;rsquo; about?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proposing using Word Mill Games&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;The Adventure Crafter&lt;/em&gt; to play or
generate &lt;em&gt;Microscope RPG&lt;/em&gt; Bookends, Periods, Events, and Scenes with &lt;em&gt;Mythic
Game Master Emulator&lt;/em&gt; sprinkled in for decision making and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lamemage.com/microscope/&#34;&gt;Microscope PRG | Lame Mage Productions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lamemage.itch.io/microscope&#34;&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/91183/Microscope&#34;&gt;DriveThruRPG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordmillgames.com/mythic.html&#34;&gt;Mythic | Word Mill Games&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/422929/Mythic-Game-Master-Emulator-Second-Edition&#34;&gt;DriveThruRPG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordmillgames.com/adventure-crafter.html&#34;&gt;The Adventure Crafter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/261479/The-Adventure-Crafter&#34;&gt;DriveThruRPG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-picture&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#the-big-picture&#34;&gt;The Big Picture&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Mythic Element Meaning Tables for inspiration as to the overarching topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bookend-history&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#bookend-history&#34;&gt;Bookend History&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;em&gt;The Adventure Crafter&lt;/em&gt; to generate &lt;code&gt;Turning Points&lt;/code&gt; for the BEGINNING and ENDING Bookends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ENDING Bookend doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a Conclusion, the future is unknown!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPTIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;: Use each &lt;code&gt;Plot Point&lt;/code&gt; as an EVENT when populating Events for Periods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPTIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;: Roll up all &lt;code&gt;Plot Points&lt;/code&gt; into the Period&amp;rsquo;s details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine &lt;code&gt;Tone&lt;/code&gt; for each Period generated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-palette&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#the-palette&#34;&gt;The Palette&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take 10 minutes to think on YES/NO items to keep/toss from your game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be honest with yourself, explore your thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write 2-5 of each list (not required).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPTIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;: Skip &lt;em&gt;The Palette&lt;/em&gt; step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacies&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#legacies&#34;&gt;Legacies&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legacies&lt;/em&gt; are common threads throughout the Periods, Events, and Scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPTIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;: Link to a MGME Thread or TAC Adventure plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;order-of-operations&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#order-of-operations&#34;&gt;Order of Operations&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found on Microscope RPG page 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the Flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declare the Focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick or Make history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask Mythic &amp;ldquo;if this is a Legacy?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forms-of-history&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#forms-of-history&#34;&gt;Forms of History&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found on Microscope RPG page 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periods (p.22)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roll a 2d6+4 for the number of Periods to roll up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust as needed, maybe 2d4 + 4 if wanting smaller numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events (p.24)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be at least 5 Events based upon the Plot Points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scenes (p.29)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scenes should come organically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;periods&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#periods&#34;&gt;Periods&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide when the Period is.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roll a die or dice that is closest to the number of Periods created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the same procedures as the Bookend History.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on Tone (Light or Dark).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your expectations or intuition. Otherwise, ask a Yes/No 50/50 CF:5 question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embellish a bit, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to use a Turning Point verbatim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to avoid NONE results in Plot Points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;events&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#events&#34;&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide when the Event is.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the Period picking method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then roll a d10 or die closest to the number of Events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the Plot Points as the basis for the Event (try to at least).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the MGME to embellish more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on the final Tone (Light or Dark).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/use-tac-with-microscope/#scenes&#34;&gt;Scenes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purpose your scene, check against Chaos Factor, just like Mythic Game Master Emulator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play out the Scene with MGME and/or your desired RPG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the Period and Event as Context for how to play your Scene and asking questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make liberal use of the MGME Meaning: Elements Tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solo Roleplay</title>
      <link>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/solo-roleplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://filbot3.github.io/posts/solo-roleplay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;sole-role-play&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&#34;Heading-link u-clickable&#34; href=&#34;https://filbot3.github.io/posts/solo-roleplay/#sole-role-play&#34;&gt;Sole Role-play&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2021 I got a big urge to play my role-playing games I had
collected before to read while playing the supposed &amp;ldquo;most popular game&amp;rdquo;. I had
all of these book and I only ever got to read them, day dream, and then go roll
a d20 and accept mediocre. So, I had the idea to search YouTube for how to play
role-playing games by yourself, and then I searched DriveThruRPG. I found a few
YouTube channels at the time that had a running story and some people talking
about game master emulators, but I thought I could do it better! I had heard
about Ironsworn, but Powered by the Apocalypse games never really groked with me
then, and I wanted to play something else. I had this stack of Genesys and Star
Wars books and dice so I made a starting scene. Long story short, the story
&amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo;, but it ultimiately fizzled out because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to drive
the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s next?&amp;rdquo; aspect. I bought a ton of supplements and most of them never
really clicked for me. That was until I bought this little red book called
Mythic Role Playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mythic Role Playing, MRPG, is a role-playing game first published in 2003 by a
little company called Word Mill Games. I say little, but it was really one
person. The author, Tana Pigeon, wrote MRPG because she felt that role-playing
games didn&amp;rsquo;t fulfill what she wanted. The Game Master Emulator section of MRPG
became popular and then Mythic Game Master Emulator, MGME, was published. For
nearly 20 years the MGME was the standard for solo role-playing for many people.
This supplement helped me learn how to design a scene, test the expectations,
and then alter or interrupt what I wanted. This allowed me to let go, trust the
tables, and exercise my interpretation of what was going on and then lean into
expectations again. However, I explored still. I then purchased the Game
Master&amp;rsquo;s Apprentice decks, ALONe, DM Yourself, and GEMulator, but nothing
resounded as much as Mythic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mythic has enlightened me and helped me master on-the-fly Game Mastering, and
also idea generation that is within the context and fiction of the universe;
even if I made it up all impromptu. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to pick up games I have and
test them out, play and learn the rules and mechanics before bringing it to the
table. Then I&amp;rsquo;ve also found my energy for reading, studying, and mastering those
rules. MGME has helped me figure out which games I actually enjoy playing rather
than conceptually from reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early 2023, Word Mill Games, Tana Pigeon, released Mythic Game Master
Emulator Second Edition with content and systems from 20 years, supplements, and
magazine articles written for the system. I look forward to Mythic Role Playing
Second Edition as well! Join the Discord group too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordmillgames.com&#34;&gt;https://www.wordmillgames.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
